Dirk Dunn

dirkdunnı@gmail.com | 336 North Delaware Ave. | North Massapequa, New York, 11758 | (516) 659 6982

Summary

I am a motivated and experienced JavaScript Developer, that puts expertise, insight, and ingenuity into building notable end to end web applications. I prefer to take an idea and bring it to life over maintaining current systems.

I look forward to the challenges I can solve for your organization.

For a more extensive view of my credentials and projects, you can refer to my

LinkedIn or personal website below: **LinkedIn:** http://linkedin.com/in/dirkdunn

Personal: http://dirkdunn.com

Education

SUNY Plattsburgh , Plattsburgh , New York

B.S. Information Technology, Graduated May 2014

SUNY Plattsburgh, Plattsburgh, New York *B.S. Psychology*, Graduated May 2014

Employment History

General Assembly, Austin, Texas

WDI Instructor, October 2016 - July 2017

Contract as an instructor for the Web Development Immersive (WDI) program in the Austin Texas area.

Responsibilities:

- Preparing & lecturing lessons
- Working with co-instructor to establish course parameters.
- Working with students to help them achieve their personal and professional goals.
- Cultivating a positive classroom culture. Attending instructor training.
- Attending office hours.

Technologies:

- HTML, CSS, JS and Git fundamentals, SPAS, BDD
- NodeJS, ExpressJS, REST, NoSQL, ORMs, Authentication, JWT API Authentication
- ReactJS, Firebase, Redux
- Python, Flask, SQL, Relational DBMS(MYSQL)

Borderfree, New York, New York

Web Engineer, January 2015 - April 2016

Help globalize online commerce by creating and implementing front end web solutions that represent the Borderfree platform.

Responsibilities:

- Working with the Moovweb SDK to proxy merchant domains.
- Creating compatibility with proxy and merchant domain by manipulating merchant's

web application to overcome come common proxy issues such as Cross-origin resource sharing, and 3rd party API authorization.

- Using front end technologies to engineer technical solutions (Javascript, CSS, SCSS).
- Integrate Borderfree web technology with merchants web application, and ensure stability throughout the customer transaction process.
- Overseeing existing web implementations and maintaining compatibility of the Borderfree proxy solution and merchant domains.
- Assist in interviewing and training new members of the engineering team.

Technologies:

- Javascript, jQuery, Grunt
- SCSS/CSS, HTML
- Git, Moovweb SDK, Tritium

Modis, New York, New York

Contract Web Developer, July 2014 - December 2014

Expert

Responsibilities:

Assisted in further developing the mobile web gifting platform for egifter.com, and the customization of food ordering templates for OLO in the greater New York area.

Technologies:

- Javascript, jQuery
- SCSS/CSS, HTML, Git
- Adobe Photoshop

Javascript:

Professional Skills

CSS: Advanced
HTML: Advanced
React.js: Intermediate
Redux: Intermediate
jQuery: Expert
NodeJS: Advanced
REST API Development: Advanced

TDD, BDD (Mocha, Chai): Intermediate noSQL: Intermediate MYSQL Workbench DBMS: Beginner Python: Intermediate Wordpress: Intermediate Ruby: Intermediate Intermediate Intermediate

Languages

English: Native

References

Mike Dang, Co-Worker General Assembly 512-762-5166 dirkdunn1@gmail.com

Dirk has an obvious passion for teaching and it shows with his lessons and the amount of time he spends preparing for them. He could have gotten through our cohorts with doing much less, but then he wouldn't have been happy with the results. He's eager to learn and has a strong thirst for knowledge, don't be surprised to hear

him getting into in-depth discussions with physics for example. **Gina Fitzgerald**, Student *General Assembly*g24fitzgerald@gmail.com

Dirk is an excellent mentor and a knowledgeable instructor who provides comprehensive lessons, and meticulous one-on-one help. With each lesson his ability to engage the class improved, and when I wanted to pursue anything beyond the scope of the class he provided the mentorship necessary for me to confidently venture into a new language or technology.